Guide to the Francille Firebaugh papers,1948-2013.
Firebaugh, Francille papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Francille Firebaugh papers, 1948-2013.
23-2-3675
Francille M., Firebaugh 1933-
5.4 cubic feet
Correspondence, Reports, Printed Materials, Subject Files, Scrapbooks, Awards, Photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, scrapbooks, and awards documenting Francille Firebaugh's career and records pertaining to her role on the Board of Trustees of Zamorano University in Honduras.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Francille Firebaugh did her undergraduate studies in dietetics and home economics education at the University of Arkansas. She completed an M.S. degree in home management and family relations at the University of Tennessee and received a Ph.D. degree in household economics and management from Cornell University. She served for 26 years in various positions at the Ohio State University and was vice provost for international affairs at the time of her Cornell appointment as Dean of the College of Human Ecology in 1988. Dean Firebaugh continued to have strong international interests at Cornell, as evidenced by her membership on the Board of Trustees of Zamorano, a Pan-American college in Honduras, and the development of ties between the College of Human Ecology and Kyoritsu Women's University in Japan.
After retiring as Dean of the College of Human Ecology (1988-1999), Francille Firebaugh served as vice provost for land grant affairs and special assistant to the president from 2000 to 2005.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, scrapbooks, and awards documenting Francille Firebaugh's career and records pertaining to her role on the Board of Trustees of Zamorano University in Honduras.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Firebaugh, Francille M.,1933-; Firebaugh, Francille M.,1933-; Cornell University--Administration.; New York State College of Human Ecology--Administration.; Zamorano University
Subjects:
Human ecology.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs, Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also collection #23-2-2817, New York State College of Human Ecology records for related material.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Material
Series II. Zamorano University
Series III. Second Malaysian Family Life Survey
Series IV. University of the South Pacific
Series V. American Association of Family and Consumer Science
Series VI. Families and Work Institute
Series VII. Awards
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Material
  - Articles about Francille Firebaugh- photos, Memorabila, 1998-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles about Francille Firebaugh- photos, Memorabila, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles about Francille Firebaugh- photos, Memorabila, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles about Francille Firebaugh- photos, Memorabila, 1951-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles about Francille Firebaugh- photos, Memorabila, 1949-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Francille Maloch-Scrapbook, Harrison County, Jefferson City, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Material- Concepts, Home, Management, General, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Wageningen--Working Party on Time Use Measurement of Household Work and its Economics Value, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh- Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence concerning Mann Library, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-biographical material, 1988, 1997-1999, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - International Conferences Attended, 1996, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Francille M. Firebaugh-Gift Acknowledgements, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Osceola High School- Reunion, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ohio State Commencement (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ohio State University's proposal to change the name of the College of Home Economics to the College of Human Ecology, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20a)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photos-Japan-American Embassy, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series II. Zamorano University
  - Zamorano:George Gardner, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Zamorano: External Reviews CIIFAD Reviews, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - By-laws, 1995, 2002, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Endowment Descriptions, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letters to Francille, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Zamorano: Dorothy Reddington, Consultant, 1999-2000, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Zamorano: Cornell Degree, 1999, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Zamorano Capital Renovation, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Zamorano Curricula, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Zamorano Director's Reports, 1999-2002 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Zamorano Development Long-Range Strategy, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Trustees and IBA Candidates, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Zamorano: Papa Fund Development, 2000-2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - AGEAP Capitulo Guatemala, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Zamorano Chapel Fund, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Trustee Giving, 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Zamorano Directors Update, 2002, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Zamorano Development Committee, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Library-Zamorano, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Zamorano Cornell, 2003, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - IFZ Trip, 2003, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 1999 March (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 1999 June (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 1999 November (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2000 March (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2000 June (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2000 October (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2001 March (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2001 November (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2002 January and March (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2002 March (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, 2003 March (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, June 2003 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, June 2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Zamorano Executive Committee, Washington DC, September 20-23, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, November 2003 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Zamorano Development KNAB, July 2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Zamorano Development KNAB, July 2004 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Zamorano Development KNAB, July 2004 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Family Foundations, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Legacy Society Zomorano, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Zamorano- Miami, March 19-21, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Board of Trustees-Zamorano, June 2004 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Board of Trustees-Zamorano, November 2004 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Country Endowments Government Support, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - ASHA, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Zamorano Study Abroad (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Alison Bixby Stone School Zamorano, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Staffing and Funding, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Zamorano Board of Directors, November 2005 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Zamorano-Annual Report, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Priority Donors-Zamorano, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Reports, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Events, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Development Committee Zamorano, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence Zamorano, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Board of Trustees Zamorano, March 2005 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Mary Ellen Flather-Zamorano Visit, May 3-4, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Zamorano- Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2005 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Strategic Plan Zamorano, 2005-2010 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Zamorano Board of Directors, March 2006 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Zamorano Board of Directors, June 2006 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Zamarono, November 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Zamorano Student Incident, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Zamorano Indigenous, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Zamorano Gifts in Kind, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Zamorano, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zamorano Development, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Zamorano Development, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Zamorano Development, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Zamorano- Annual Report, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Planned Giving, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Foundation, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Kovary Consultancy, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Zamorano Directories, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Board of Trustees - Zamorano, March 2007 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees - Zamorano, June 2007 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Academic Committee, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Zamorano Cornell Interns, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Zamorano: Search for Development Office, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Zamorano Development Organization, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees, November 2007 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Zamorano Annual Report, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Development Committee, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Zamorano Curriculum Review, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Retreat, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Zamorano, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Zamorano President's Report, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Zamorano Annual Reports and Master Plan, 2008-2009 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Zamorano Academic Committee Meeting Minutes, 2008-2011 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Zamorano Executive Committee Meetings, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Zamorano Institutional Advancement Committee, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meetings, January, March 2009 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2009 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Zamorano Institutional Advancement Committee Meeting Minutes, 2009-2011 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Zamorano Institutional Advancement Committee Meeting Minutes, 2009-2011 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, November 2009 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, March 2010 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Symposium of Zamorano in the United States, May 2011 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2010 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, November 2010 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meetings, March 2011 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Zamorano Institutional Advancement Committee, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Zamorano Buildings and Grounds Committee; RCG Objectives, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, March 2011 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2011 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, November 2011 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, March 2012 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2012 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Zamorano International Board of Advisors; Endowment Policies, 1997-2010 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, March 2013 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Zamorano Board of Trustees Meeting, June 2013 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Series III. Second Malaysian Family Life Survey
  - Malaysia, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Second Malaysian Family Life Survey, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Second Malaysian Family Life Survey, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Series IV. University of the South Pacific
  - University of the South Pacific School of Agriculture, 2004, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - University of South Pacific, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - University of the South Pacific Reports, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - University of the South Pacific Proposal and Funding, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - University of the South Pacific Demand Study, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - The University of the South Pacific Concept Paper, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The University of the South Pacific Graduation, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - University of the South Pacific, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Buffett, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Cornell Higher Education Research Institute Advisory Board, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - The University of the South Pacific, 2006-2010 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - The University of the South Pacific Triennial Submission, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The University of the South Pacific A Vision for the year 2020 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Series V. American Association of Family and Consumer Science
  - American Association of Family and Consumer Science, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - American Association of Family and Consumer Science, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Series VI. Families and Work Institute
  - Families and Work Institute (FWI), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - FWI Board, December 12, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - FWI Board of Trustees, July 2007 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - FWI Board, December 2007 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - FWI Finance Committee, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Series VII. Awards
  - The College of Education and Human Ecology Hall of Fame, November 2, 2007 (Box 4)
  - Department of Agriculture, William Henry Hatch, Hatch Act, includes Francille's lecture, November 10, 2002 (Box 4)
  - For Distinguished Service to the Ohio State University, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Council Administrative Board, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - The Ohio State University Distinguished Service Award, August, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Helen Bull Vandervort Alumni Achievement Award, June 10, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1998-1999, 2005 (Box 4)
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International (Box 4)
  - Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research for dedicated service, November 13, 1996 (Box 5)
  - The American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences, Distinguished Service Award, June 26, 1995 (Box 5)